Television Press Kit Collection
Television Press Kit Collection
1966-2002
1981-1996
34 linear ft.
Collection contains selected press kits from ABC, CBS, Discovery, Fox, NBC, Saban, WB, and UPN for network programming and from the Television Critics Association and National Cable Forum for cable networks. Some kits also contain photographs and CD-ROMS. Dates of coverage vary.
1650744
Biographical History
A press kit is a prepackaged set of promotional material. In the case of television shows, press kits often include still shots from the show, a page with sketches and brief bios of main characters, a summary of the main themes or aspects of the show, and sample posters, contained in or printed on an illustrated custom folder or packet.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Television Press Kit Collection contains selected press kits for programming for a wide range public, network and cable television stations. Networks represented are ABC, CBS, Discovery, Fox, NBC, PBS, Saban Entertainment, Showtime, Synditel, The WB, and UPN.
Also included are press kits for the Television Critics Association/National Cable Forum, which cover the following cable channels. Not all channels are present for all dates.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is divided by television station and within that, material is arranged (mostly) alphabetically; in most cases regular television shows come first followed by specials.
Related Material
has a number of television-related collections. Please refer to for a complete listing. For other press kits, see the Movie Press Kit Collection and the
Cartoon Press Kit Collection
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; American Broadcasting Company.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Discovery Channel (Firm); National Broadcasting Company.; Public Broadcasting Service (U.S.); Television Critics Association (U.S.); Twentieth Century-Fox Television, Inc.; Television -- United States -- Marketing.; Television -- United States -- Public relations.; Press kits.; Advertisers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Some press kits gift of Steven H. Scheuer.
Inventory
- ABC
  - Network programming, 1966/67 (Box 1)
  - Network programming, 1981/82 (Box 1)
  - Network programming, 1982/83 (Box 1)
  - Network programming, 1984/85 (Box 2)
  - Network programming, 1986/87 (Box 2)
  - Network programming, 1990/91 (Box 3)
  - Network programming, 1995/96 (Box 4)
  - Network programming, 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - Network programming, 2000-2002 (Box 6)
- CBS
  - Network programming, 1974/75 (Box 7)
  - Network programming, 1978/79 (Box 7)
  - Network programming, 1979/80 (Box 7)
  - Network programming, 1981/82 (Box 8)
  - Network programming, 1982/83 (Box 8)
  - Network programming, 1983/84 (Box 8)
  - Network programming, 1984/85 (Box 9)
  - Network programming, 1985/86 (Box 9)
  - Network programming, 1986/87 (Box 10)
  - Network programming, 1994/95 (Box 10)
  - Network programming, 1995/96 (Box 10)
  - Network programming, 1997-2000 (Box 11)
  - Network programming, 2000-2003 (Box 12)
- CNN
  - News programming, 1985 (Box 10)
- Discovery Communications, Inc.
  includes a CD-Rom with artwork
  - Discovery Channel Cable programming, 1995/96 (Box 10)
  - The Learning Channel Cable programming, 1995/96 (Box 10)
- FOX
  - Network programming, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Network programming, 1995/96 (Box 13)
  - Network programming, 1997-1999 (Box 14)
  - Network programming, 1998-2000 (Box 15)
  - Network programming, 2000-2002 (Box 16)
- HBO
  - Cable programming, 1995 (Box 17)
  - Cable programming, 1999-2002 (Box 17)
- MTV
  - Cable programming, 2001 (Box 18)
- NBC
  - Network programming, 1978/79 (Box 19)
  - Network programming, 1983/84 (Box 19)
  - Network programming, 1985/86 (Box 20)
  - Network programming, 1994/95 (Box 20)
  - Network programming, 1995/96 (Box 20)
  - Network programming, 1996-1999 (Box 21)
  - Network programming, 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - Network programming, 2001-2002 (Box 23)
  - Noble House, James Clavell, 1987; mini-series (Box 23)
- PAX
  - Network programming, 1999/2000 (Box 24)
- PBS
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring 1988 (Box 24)
  - Public programming Pledge Drive, March 1988 (Box 24)
  - Public programming, Winter, 1989 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter, Fall 1992 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer, Fall 1993 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Fall 1994 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer, Fall 1995 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer 1996 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Fall 1996 (Box 24)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer, Fall 1997 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer 1998 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer, Fall 1999 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, Winter/Spring, Summer 2000 (Box 24A)
  - Public programming, 1998-2002 (Box 24)
- Saban Entertainment
  - American television programming, 1995/96 (Box 25)
  - American television programming, 1996/97 (Box 25)
- Showtime
  - Cable programming, 1999-2002 (Box 25)
- Synditel
  - Programming, 1993 (Box 25)
- Television Critics Association/National Cable Forum
  - Cable programming Networks, November, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, June, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, June, 1986 (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, January 1987 (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, (Possibly 1995) (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Cable programming Networks, 1998-2000 (Box 30)
  - Cable programming Networks, 2000-2002 (Box 31)
- The WB Television Network
  - Network programming, 1/11/95 (Box 27)
  - Primetime and Kids WB, July 8, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Primetime and Kids WB, 1996-1998 (Box 28)
  - Primetime and Kids WB, 1999-2001 (Box 32)
  - Primetime and Kids WB, 2001-2002 (Box 33)
- UPN
  - Network programming, 1994 (Box 29)
  - Network programming, 1995/96 (Box 29)
  - Network programming, 1996/97 (Box 29)
  - Network programming, 2000 (Box 34)
- Miscellaneous
  - Charge accounts, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Prudential securities, 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 33)